## **David Trail**

CONTACT 11/6 Watson Crescent Mobile: +44 7816 930 167 INFORMATION Edinburgh Email: mr.dj.trail@gmail.com

EH11 1HB DoB: 8th of January 1990

About Me

What I'm looking for more than anything is to get into a Senior DevOps role, that has been my number one priority for the past two years and what I see myself doing for the foreseeable future. I have already made great strides towards that end in my own time and by selecting work for clients involved in high level Linux sysadmin and DevOps related technologies. I know that my current Linux sysadmin abilities are extremely good as I have been running dedicated and cloud servers and VPSs since 2006, I have run them since before I started at university and continue to administer

Though freelancing I've taught myself a great many skills in the world of sysadmin/DevOps but what I'm really looking for now is to hone those skills to perfection in a permanent work environment.

#### WORK HISTORY

## Freelance Linux System Administrator

September 2014 until today

them to this day.

- Repeat contracts for numerous clients generally in the area of Linux DevOps/sysadmin/software engineering
- Technologies include: Docker, Qemu/KVM, OpenVPN, Puppet, Python, Perl, Bash, AWS (Cloud Formation, EC2, S3, ...), Cloud-Flare, Git, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Nginx/Apache/uwsgi, etc
- Duties include: migration, configuration and set-up, security, service optimisation, monitoring, benchmarking, auto-scaling, networking, . . .

Client: Leo Hämäläinen

- Leo has been my client for the past  $\approx 7$  months
- I have been contracted as a Linux sysadmin for their operations at devoca.fi, a backend for their hand-held label device and other products with hundreds of clients throughout Finland and elsewhere who rely on Devoca's servers to operate
- Duties have included: Upscaling operations; troubleshooting downtime; eradicating a rootkit that they'd contracted under a previous contractor; optimising both Apache and MySQL's configurations; planning for minimal downtime during migration periods; masterslave MySQL mirroring; backup script writing

- Technologies include: Apache Servermix, Apache HTTP, Exim mail server (MTA), Ubuntu 14.04, iptables firewall, fail2ban, MySQL, DKIM + SPF, DNS
- Communication has been key to my success in this role

#### Client: CloudWorks

- I was contracted to set up a continuous deployment strategy utilising AWS's Cloud Formation, EC2 and RDS alongside a Puppet master server to manage the deployed servers. This required writing from scratch a Cloud Formation script with a variable number of EC2 instances which would image themselves from an AMI which would connect to a Puppet master server and auto-configure themselves with an app hosted on Github.
- This has been the most challenging but also most enjoyable role I have done so far. Working within Linux, AWS and DevOps is where I feel completely at home and find myself loving the work that I do, impressing myself with my own abilities.
- Technologies: AWS, EC2, RDS, Route53, Puppet, PostgreSQL, troposphere, cloud-config, Cloud Formation

#### Freelance Software Engineer

July 2013 to September 2014 (1 year 2 months)

- Several large projects using Django + Python
- Web development
- $\bullet$  Postgres + MySQL
- Bitcoin trading, investment and development
- Linux system administration

# Client: Éric Bisceglia

- Worked with Éric and another software engineer for  $\approx 6$  months
- Containerising app instances to provide security in case of a security breach, ensuring uptime and redundancy for the web frontend/PostgreSQL backend on Microsoft's Azure platform

## Software Engineer, Scotweb

June 2011 to July 2013 (2 years 1 month)

- Commercial web development and maintenance
- Linux system administration
- Twisted Python / Python development
- Full stack deployment and configuration
- Web development (HTML/CSS/jQuery)

#### Village Orderly, Aberdeenshire council

July 2007 to September 2010 (3 years, 2 months)

#### Kitchen Porter, Valentinos restaurant

June 2004 to June 2006 (2 years)

### **EDUCATION**

## Computer Science BSc, **Heriot-Watt University** September 2007 to May 2011

$2^{\rm nd}$ year	3 <sup>rd</sup> year	4 <sup>th</sup> year
Database Management	Artificial Intelligence	Distributed Systems
Discreet Mathematics	Operating Systems	Parallel Technologies
Internet Communications	Computer Graphics	Data Mining
Software Design	Professional Development	Machine Learning
Formal Specifications	Concurrency	Biological computation

## OTHER

- Achieved Intermediate 1 Spanish (Escuela de Idiomas)
- $\bullet$  Raised £1,050 for MND Scotland in a charity Skydive
- Maintain Github and Bitbucket profiles
- Always up to date with the latest technologies in DevOps and Software Engineering

Name	Dr. Greg Michaelson	Mr. Steve Tuttle
Relation	Project supervisor	Client (DevOps, AWS)
Email	G.Michaelson@hw.ac.uk	swt@drinkme.com
Phone	$+44\ 131\ 451\ 3422$	$+61\ 400\ 601\ 689$